This is Trigun.
Oh, my God.
Hey, boss, how long are you going to
keep me held up in this place, huh?
He got two of our idiots already while
we sat around twiddling our thumbs.
You should have let me handle it.
That's what you should have done.
All right, then, I'll let you go next.
I'll even set the stage for you.
I expect you to entertain him
with a unique performance of Trix.
You can be reasoned with.
Let's hope the reward is reasonable.
So, are you gonna make him
go at it alone this time?
Hardly.
I'm a firm believer
that an audience always
gets more pleasure from
a drama with a twist.
It's a simple formula.
The greater the tragedy, the
greater the emotional effect.
I'm worried, Meryl.
It's been two whole weeks now.
I'm sorry this is as far
as we can travel together.
Why?
It's your job or your life.
Which is more important to you?
I can't explain now.
If I did, you'd be put in danger.
So it's been a lot of fun, but...
Well, I guess that's all!
Poor Mr.
Vash, I wonder how he's doing.
You know him, he's undoubtedly
goofing around in some town somewhere.
I'm sure he's just fine and dandy.
Wait for me!
Hey, did you hear?
Remember the guy in the white suit who
had caused the saloon riot the other day?
Well, he apparently turned
out to be one of Vash's gang.
Oh, yeah.
That would explain a lot, including
why his methods were so dang vicious.
But he took off.
Yeah, that's right.
I guess at this point, we should count
our blessings if we got off so easy.
Yeah, he's a devil in a red coat.
That's what he is.
Damn, I wish he'd just dropped dead.
How can you stand there and say
such awful things about him?
Huh?
I mean, after all, you have no
idea what kind of person he is.
I think you're disgusting.
Huh?
Gee, Meryl.
Walk your own path with
your head held high.
I just have to keep saying it.
Right.
Millie? Yes?
We've got to get going.
We have a lot of work ahead.
Let's stop wasting time. Okay.
If necessary, we'll follow
him to the ends of the Earth.
It's not only our job now, it's
become our mission to track him down.
Hello, chair, how you been?
Legato, I am the one that
is hunting you this time.
I will find you whatever it takes.
That sounds real cool in
my head, but in reality,
I haven't got a clue as to
how I'm going to find him.
Oh man, what am I gonna do?
Not only that, the more time
I have to think about it,
the more frightening it becomes, and now
my knees are starting to knock together.
Oh man, I actually have to fight this guy!
How can I possibly win such a
battle or even have a chance to
survive a fight with the guy
who smiles with those evil eyes?
The answer is I can't.
I'm gonna be slaughtered.
That's all.
It's not even funny.
I should just back out.
That's what I should do, all right?
Yeah, yeah, for once I'm right. Yeah.
You're right about one thing.
You're not funny.
You change your tune
faster than radio station.
Yeah, well, life ought to
be fun after all, right?
No.
Hey, that's super tasty, mister.
I'll have another salmon
sandwich if you don't mind.
Augusta, I'll be waiting for
you at Augusta Fastestampede.
You will acknowledge
my request immediately.
If you do not meet my request, this is
a sample of what will happen. Don't!
Why?
Who did this?
There's no blood. Huh? What?
Do you actually know him?
This guy, you know him?
It must be him.
He's the only one capable of doing this.
Legato.
You called him?
He's your friend?
Hey, is he your friend?
Do you want me there so bad you
would kill the innocent to get me?
All right.
I'll go there, Legato.
I'll face you on your home ground.
Hey, who are you?
Me?
Who the heck are you?
Hey, easy there, pal.
Where's the fire?
Listen, it's Vash the Stampede.
He's here. I'm telling you.
Oh, my gosh.
Are you sure about that?
Yeah, he's running
rampant through Augusta,
blasting away with that
big silver gun of his.
It's true.
That crazy bastard's gonna do
to Augusta what he did to July.
Well, it's a good thing we found him.
Hmm, what in the hell could
that man possibly be thinking?
My name is...
Vash the Stampede!
Ladies and gentlemen,
forgive the lack of warning, but I'm
afraid it's time for my daily massacre!
And if you don't believe
I'm the real thing,
take a long look at me
and start freaking out!
Observe my red coat,
my lovely blonde locks, And
if you're still having doubts,
check out my one hundred
percent accurate gunmanship!
If you people don't want to die today,
get at least a hundred miles away
from this place as fast as you can,
and then happily ever after!
Finally, that's the last of them.
Why couldn't that nihilistic jerk
have picked a better location?
I used up all my energy
just chasing people out.
I'm poofed.
I don't like this.
It reminds me of the last time.
Something's not right here unless you...
Blood!
Do you like my decorations?
In this game, losers don't get to go home.
They go to hell.
Did you kill them?
I am the fifth gung-ho gun.
My name is E .G. Mann.
Did you kill them or not?
Damn, you are a noisy one, aren't you?
What if I did, chicken shit?
You don't seem to want to kill anyone, so
someone had to step up and cover your ass.
And besides Blondie, you
have fallen into my court,
gee, aren't you the poetic one?
Are you telling me that I only have
two choices, to die or to let die?
Whoa, cowboy, don't be such a drama queen!
Only one more has to die.
Just stand there like a good boy.
As soon as I take you
down, it'll all be over.
What?
What's going on?
That bastard is trying
to cut in on my action.
If I have chosen to dispatch
my saber at this time,
the situation may have
escalated into a real problem.
You would have at least been knocked
senseless by your humanoid typhoon there.
Sure, right?
Well, now it's getting interesting.
Looks like you're the favorite.
What's your name?
Forgive my lack of manners.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am the ninth gung-ho gun of Jigenzan.
Trained by the masters of the Ito
school, I am Raidei, the blade.
I hold no personal grudge against you, but
I wish to engage you in Shi 'ai. Shi 'ai?
I can't read that!
If you cannot mean Japanese, then I'll
give you an abbreviated explanation.
It's a fight to the death.
What's in it for you?
You playing along with
Legato's little farce as well?
I would happily walk the path
of carnage a thousand times,
and a thousand times again
for the mastery of Bushido.
What?
Because there is something only visible
when you stand before the Deathly Abyss.
I believe you have seen
this too, have you not?
I haven't seen anything there at all.
Except my own fear.
That's too bad.
that I think you should experience.
Hey!
That mental state!
Come on, now.
It's my job to slice and dice this guy.
Ridiculous.
It would appear you simply did not hear
what I told you just a few minutes ago.
You're right.
I didn't.
What? Huh? Huh?
Your match was quite
over before my arrival.
That fast gunmanship.
Words fail to describe its greatness.
That man was never an
opponent to be humbled by you.
You were completely out of your lead.
Your turn is over.
Take heart in the fact that you may
have served to amuse him for a moment.
You... slime.
Yes, let it burn within you.
I feel it build and fester.
Angry aura released through your
every pore, my knees are shaking.
That alone makes my trip
to this place worthwhile.
It is the source of my greatest pleasure.
Come on, I'm in your debt. Ready?
Is that all you got?
Cause me real harm!
Never heard of warrior's compassion?
I can't hit you in any
way if it'd kill you.
Quite the arrogance.
A real eyesore.
It blurs my path to spiritual awareness.
My friend, people don't
change their ways that easily.
You actually think we're People, absurd!
You and I are men, yet not of
we are dark, diabolical puppets.
What we are—our demons.
demons
Wow, what is that?
I don't know, but it's
definitely not a good thing.
You're right.
Do you think it's Vash?
We've got to help him.
Let's go!
Wait, Meryl!
What's wrong?
We can't this time. Mr.
Vash said it's too big for us to handle.
This is seriously dangerous.
I am well aware of the danger, Millie.
Meryl!
Why don't you stop wasting time
here and fight me like you mean it?
Ah! Fight me!
Now that was a huge shockwave.
Oh, no big deal.
Nothing I can't dodge.
Can't you make those bullets hit me?
Ah!
Come on, knowledge boy!
Compassion?
In the heat of battle?
This is a gross disappointment.
I can't believe it.
Vash the stampede.
Is this all you amount to?
I see absolutely nothing!
Tell me!
At least give me an answer!
Tell me what you're seeing
right now at this moment!
Tell me!
Do you intend to die, Vash the Stampede?
The time has come for you to use it.
Go ahead, use it.
Use it!
There's something only you can do.
Use it! Quickly!
Stop it!
Stop!
Coward.
I cannot believe he is
begging for his life.
What is that?
Don't do that!
Not... the light!
Oh my god!
Mr.
Bash meant what he said!
Just look at this place! Where is he?
We've gotta find him!
Meryl, where are you going?
Let go of me!
Let go of me right now, Millie!
Put me down!
Millie, I want to go back! Wait!
I have to go back there!
What is this strange phenomenon?
Is this some sort of
twisted Christian science?
Stop!
Stop it now!
Stop it!
What is this indescribable horror
coursing through my entire body?
Is this it?
Is this the moment I have been seeking?
How do I really reach spiritual awareness?
No!
This thing before me!
Run!
Run away now!
No! Run!
What? What is that?
I don't understand!
What the hell is that thing?
Stop it! Stop it! Please! Help me! No!
No!
What the...
What is that horrific light?
Is he the one creating that?
Vash the Stampede?
Yes, this is the second time.
The first was a great explosion,
which took July 23 years ago.
Billy, please let me go!
I have to go back!
I can't do that!
Besides, if you die,
you'll never see him again!
No, look!
A hole in the moon!
I felt... a terror!
Only you can survive something like that.
Who...
who are you?
What happened to Vash the Stampede?
I don't know. Damn.
If we act quickly, we may be able to defeat
that man, that horrible devil of a man.
The stampede is too
dangerous to be left alive.
If you help me, we can do this together.
I can't do that.
Are you insane?
What's the matter with you?
You and I are...
we could...
I'm sorry.
Sure, nobody died from the blast.
But just look at this.
Another town in rubble.
Is this the path you have chosen?
Is this it?
Vash the Stampede?
Hey, did you hear the rumor about how the
humanoid typhoon showed up on Augusta?
I sure did.
You know, they say he managed to
destroy the entire city all by himself.
First July, and now Augusta.
What in the hell can
that maniac be thinking?
He's completely out of control.
It's just getting out of hand.
The bounty on his head
will only get bigger now.
And who's to say won't destroy
our town and any others?
I'm starting to believe it's all his
fault that we're stuck on this planet.
Not to mention all of the other
crap I've heard about him.
But there's more.
They're saying now that he's also solely
responsible for that big hole in the moon.
It makes me sick just to think about it.
What are you, nuts?
There isn't a man alive who
can pull off a stunt like that.
Cool your jets, will ya?
I'm just telling you what I heard.
I'm not making it up.
Hey at this point.
Maybe we should just be thankful
that we're all still alive.
Yeah, you said it
Meryl we received a letter
from the main office.
It's about time
Well, the correspondence
certainly is slow.
We've been sitting here
waiting for two weeks
Meryl Stryfe and Millie Thompson are to
return to the main office immediately.
Furthermore,
in a conference held the other day,
it was decided that Vash the
Stampede will be designated?
as mankind's first
official human disaster.
From this day forward, no matter
what kind of damage he causes,
the Bernardelli Insurance
Society will be...
will be...
...uninvolved.
This can't be.
What do they think will change
by making this decision now?
Meryl...
Mr.
Vash, you're a jerk!
You made Meryl cry!
I'll never, ever forgive you for this!
The blue sky in the middle of the
sky, the wind is in the future.
The light of the sky, as
you can see, as you can see.
It's just that it's been released.
Just for a long time.
If there's nothing left for me.
If there's nothing
left for me.
I'm not sure how much I can find a dream.
This is the first time
I'm going to see you.
It's just a little bit more.
I'm not sure how much I can find it.
I'm not
sure
how
much I can find it.
Rem told me that someone
she loved died on Earth.
She told me she boarded this
ship so she could start over.
What does it feel like to
have someone you love die?
I tried thinking of what it
would be like if Rem died.
When I did, hot water came out of my eyes
and it wouldn't stop for a long time.
Rem, I'll always be there for you.
I won't leave you alone.